# Frédéric Dubouchet

frederic.dubouchet@gmail.com | +41 79 104 85 76

# RESUME OBJECTIVE

Senior software engineer in the computer engineering sector for more than 20 years, including at some of the biggest companies (Nagra, CERN, Google), the experience I have accumulated can provide solutions in embedded, big data, microservices, and machine learning. I have been teaching C++ at the bachelor and master level for about two years and find it enjoyable. With my experience and contacts, I can be a valuable addition to the company.

# **EDUCATION**

## **HES-SO // MASTER**

MSE IN INFORMATION AND

COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES

2011 - 2013 | Lausanne, CH Thesis: (6 / 6) - Betatron tune measurement with the LHC damper using a GPU

## HES-SO // HEPIA

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

**2002 - 2005 | Geneva, CH** Thesis: (5.5 / 6) - 3D stereoscopy

#### **EPFL**

COMPUTER SCIENCE

1997 - 1999 | Lausanne, CH Unfinished - Founded Eleaf Sarl

## MATURITÉ

Type S. scientifique

1997 | Geneva, CH

Grad. (74 / 90) - Swiss secondary school degree

## LINKS

Github://anirul

LinkedIn:// Frédéric Dubouchet

# COURSEWORK

## **MASTER**

Artificial Intelligence + Practicum

Cryptography

Software Security

Optimizations

Fourrier and Wavelets

Web Data Mining

GPU computing

Cloud computing

#### **BASHELOR**

Digital Signal Processing Compilers + Practicum Theory of Computation Operating Systems Databases

Virtual Marchine + Practicum Computer Graphics + Practicum

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **CONTRACT WORK** | CONTRACTOR

July 2020 - Now | Sion, CH

Work in the domain of (AI/ML), 3D graphics, and networks

- Toolset for Unreal Engine 4 (C++)
- Implementation of network protocol (C#/nat-pmp)
- Distributed computing and capturing hardware (C++/gRPC)

# ORIGINAL SCORE | FOUNDER

March 2019 - Now | Lens, CH

Create a game to release on Steam

- Organizing with Editors and financial sector
- Managing a team of graphists and game designers

## **GOOGLE** | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

October 2015 - February 2019 | Zurich, CH

Working on Google Shopping from anti-spam to database

- Database writing for the Google Shopping group (C++/OpenCV/gRPC)
- Reviewing process for online automatic purchase (C++/Javascript/Java)
- Version checking system from online automatic purchase (C++/git/gRPC)

## IDIAP RESEARCH INSTITUT | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

August 2014 - August 2015 | Martigny, CH

Developer for research projects

- Teaching computer vision to researchers (C++/OpenCL/OpenCV)
- Robotic and computer vision projects (C++/OpenCL/CUDA/OpenCV)
- Automatic Speech Recognition (Python)

## **EPFL - MOKASTUDIO** | Senior Software Engineer

February 2014 - July 2014 | Lausanne, CH

CTI project for a 3D animation and inverse kinematic application

• Writing a full forward scene graph (C++)

## **CERN** | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2006 - December 2013 | Geneva, CH

Software and drivers for controlling custom hardware board in a realtime environment, on LynxOS and then Linux

- Leader for the Linac4 RF control system (C++)
- LHC RF Beam control: architecture, coordination, implementation (C++)
- ADT damper: architecture, coordination, implementation (C++/OpenCL)

## **NAGRAVISION** | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2000 - 2002 | Lausanne, CH

Content management and encryptions for digital television

- Porting the software from Win32 to Linux and TRU64 UNIX (C/C++)
- Multiplexer driver for digital trelevision (C)

## **ELEAF SARL** | FOUNDER, SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

1999 - 2000 | Geneva, CH

Web backend development

- COM objects for Web/ASP FTP, POP3, IMAP interfaces (C++)
- Multimedia Java Applets (Java)

# TFACHING

## **SAE** | Creative Media Education

September 2020 - August 2021 | Geneva, CH

- Beginner lecture (C++)
- How to implement a basic physic engine (C++)
- Computer Graphics (OpenGL/C++)
- Optimization (C++/OpenCL/CUDA/Assembly)

# EPAC | ÉCOLE PROFESSIONNELLE DES ARTS CONTEMPORAINS

September 2019 - July 2020 | Saxon, CH

- 3D infographics and game techonologies (C++/OpenGL/gRPC/Socket/...)
- Handling of Unreal 4 (C++/Blueprint)

#### **SAE** | CREATIVE MEDIA EDUCATION

February 2019 - Now | once per month | Geneva, CH

- Game Engine technologies (C++/Socket/...)
- Handling of Unreal 4 (C++/Blueprint)

## SGA | SWISS GAME ACADEMY

August 2016 | July 2019 | Fribourg, CH

• Handling of Unreal 4 (Blueprint)

# RESEARCH

## **CERN** | GRADUATE RESEARCH

July 2013 - December 2013 | Geneva, CH

Betatron tune measurement with the LHC damper using a GPU with Prof. Paul Albuquerque and Dr. Wolfgang Höfle during my master thesis. A system to make real-time Fourier transform on GPU to better react to instabilities in the LHC beam using the ADT damper. It was on display at the IBIC 2013 conference in Oxford, UK.

## **HEPIA** | Undergraduate Research

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013 | Geneva, CH

I made a simple comparison of OpenCL and CUDA performances for the **Hepia**. Implementation of various algorithms using OpenCL, available on **GitHub**.

# SKILLS

## LANGUAGE | NATURAL

French Mother tongue

English Fluent
German Rusted
Japanese Beginner

## **TECHNICAL** | Languages & OS

#### Over 100'000 lines

- (
- ( ++

#### • Over 10'000 lines

- Assembly
- C#
- Java
- JavaScript
- Json
- Protocol Buffers

#### • Over 1'000 lines

- gRPC
- ATEX
- Lua
- Python
- XML/XSD

#### Familiar

- cmake
- git
- PostgreSQL
- Unreal Blueprint
- VCPKG

#### OS

- FreeBSD
- Linux
- macOS
- Windows

# AWARDS AND PROJECTS

Biolite miniDHT Biolite Reloaded MOLA Parser See Mark CPPS UE4 Mirages Meow Zedong, Green Revenge Maneki Neko, Isotops Meow Zedong 2,	96k game network game research game research game game game game game	C++,DirectX C++,protobuf C++,Irrlicht C++ C++,Irrlicht Blueprint Blueprint Blueprint Blueprint Blueprint C++,Blueprint C++,Blueprint	2 <sup>nd</sup> at Breakpoint 6 <sup>th</sup> at Breakpoint Distributed Hash Table (P2P) 1 <sup>st</sup> at Buenzli Parsing of NASA Mars Orbital Laser Altimetry Epic Game Jam Multiscreen setup for use in an earthquake simulator Global Game Jam Epic Game Jam Epic Game Jam Epic Game Jam Nordic Game Jam Epic Game Jam
Mini Epic City Builder Frame Jnreal Mine Sweeper Plugin	game engine demo	C++ C++,OpenGL C++	Epic Game Jam 3D Engine (Bloom, PBR, SSAO, Deffered Rendering,) Mine sweeper as a plugin for Unreal 4.
		'_ '	
日で日くることという	Biolite AniniDHT Biolite Reloaded MOLA Parser Gee Mark CPPS UE4 Mirages Meow Zedong, Green Revenge Maneki Neko, Botops Meow Zedong 2, Mini Epic City Builder Grame	Biolite 96k game niniDHT network Biolite Reloaded game MOLA Parser research Gee Mark game CPPS UE4 research Mirages game Meow Zedong, game Green Revenge game Maneki Neko, game Sotops game Meow Zedong 2, game Mini Epic City Builder game frame engine	niniDHT Riolite Reloaded Riolite Reloade